Guide to the Acton Visual Materials at La Pietra MSS.LaPietra.001
Villa La Pietra
- Series II: Villa La Pietra
  - Subseries B: The Interior and the Collection
    - 5 Historic Albums mostly of the interior and works of art at present in the Collection or probably formerly once belonging to it.
      - Folder 2. Album labelled "VIII Sculture"
        - XXI. B.13., undated; cuid6390 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 9)
          SCULTURA in legno dipinto in policromia: Madonna col Bambino. h. 42,5 Scultore veneto della seconda metà del XIV secolo. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. See also II.B.1.XXI. B.13.-1.14.-42.
        - XIX. E.8., undated; cuid6391 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 10)
          SCULTURA in legno scolpito e dipinto in policromia: Buddha seduto. h. 84 Cina, Dinastia Sung (?). Numbered 758. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background.
        - XX. C.9., undated; cuid6392 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 11)
          STATUETTE (coppia) di Europa e Africa in terracotta dipinta e policromata. Europa: corno dell'abbondanza, cavallo, tiara e simboli del potere temporale Africa: copricapo con elefante, serpenti, e fascio di spighe. h. 52 Mozzi, XVIII secolo. (Detail of Europa).
        - IX. A.9., undated; cuid6393 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 12)
          RILIEVO in terracotta policroma entro cornice centinata a tabernacolo: Madonna col Bambino. h. 83 l. 67 Bottega di Donatello, XV secolo. See also II.B.1.IX. A.9.-1.12.-21.
        - XX. C.9., undated; cuid6394 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 12)
          STATUETTE (coppia) di Europa e Africa in terracotta dipinta e policromata. Europa: corno dell'abbondanza, cavallo, tiara e simboli del potere temporale Africa: copricapo con elefante, serpenti, e fascio di spighe. h. 52 Mozzi, XVIII secolo. Detail of Africa. See also II.B.1.XX. C.9.13.-95.
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.XX. C.9.13.-95., undated; cuid6395 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 13)
        - XV. A.1., undated; cuid6396 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 14)
          STATUETTA in terracotta dipinta di bruno su base lignea: Giovane con cestino di frutta. h. 46 Manifattura napoletana (?) del XVIII secolo. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. See also II.B.1.XV. A.1.-1.12.-117.
        - LIII. A.27., undated; cuid6397 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 15)
          STATUETTA in legno scolpito e dipinto in policromia: Accattone. h. 50 Intagliatore francese del XVIII secolo. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. See also II.B.1.LIII. A.27.19.-21.
        - XXXII. D.10., undated; cuid6398 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 16)
          STATUETTA in terracotta modellata a tutto tondo e dipinta: San Sebastiano. h. 66,5 Artista fiorentino della prima metà del XVI secolo. Numbered 354. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. See also II.B.1.XXXII. D.10.17.-87.
        - XX. C.9., undated; cuid6399 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 17)
          STATUETTE (coppia) di Europa e Africa in terracotta dipinta e policromata. Europa: corno dell'abbondanza, cavallo, tiara e simboli del potere temporale Africa: copricapo con elefante, serpenti, e fascio di spighe. h. 52 Mozzi, XVIII secolo. Only detail of Europa.
        - Statuette of (Tobias and the angel) (also in Historic Album VI, page 2). Closely related to XXVI. B.2., undated; cuid6400 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 18)
        - XXXI. E.5., undated; cuid6401 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 19)
        - LIII. A.27., undated; cuid6402 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 20)
        - XXI. E.5., undated; cuid6403 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 21)
          SCULTURA in legno dipinto: Madonna col Bambino. h. 90 l. 31 Scultore abruzzese (?) del XIII (?) secolo. Number 251. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. See also II.B.1.XXI. E.5.-3.14.-57.
        - XIX. E.8., undated; cuid6404 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 22)
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.IX. A.9.-1.12.-21., undated; cuid6405 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 23)
        - XXXII. A.16., undated; cuid6406 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 24)
          BUSTO in terracotta modellata a tutto tondo e patinata con interventi di colore su base lignea dipinta. h. 36,5 base: h. 9 l. 44,5 Modellatore del XV (?), XIX secolo. Numbered 139 and annotated on the page "Allievo Donatello - Nanni di Bartolo" Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. See also II.B.1.XXXII. A.16.-3.17.-34.
        - XXI. B.6., undated; cuid6407 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 25)
          BOZZETTO di Torso virile in terracotta modellata su base di marmo intarsiato. h. 33 base: h. 17 Artista italiano del XVI secolo. Numbered 282. Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background.
        - XXX. E.10., undated; cuid6408 (Box 29, Photo-album VIII., Page 26)
          SCULTURA in terracotta modellata a tutto tondo: S. Giovannino nel deserto. h. 30 l. 40 Bottega fiorentina del XVI secolo. Numbered 47., and annotated on the recto "Florentine" Photographed presumably in the Sala da Pranzo with the painting of the Coronation of the Virgin, XXXII. A.11. visible in the background. Also in Historic Album V, page 88.
      - Folder 3. Album labelled "IX Doppione"
        This is canvas-bound album with photos almost all of painted panels and screens or furniture in the interior of Villa La Pietra (series II.B.1.), in one of the Villas (series II.C.) or a work of art illustrating the Actons' activity as collectors (series IV.A.). None of these were pasted on to the page and so they were all removed in 2004 and replaced by Color photocopies. A number of pages at the end of the album are un-numbered and without photos. The pages are not numbered but many of the photographs are numbered on the page on labels, and these have not been countersigned with a 'tick'. Some of the pages also bear initials and a second label, sometimes blank and sometimes with another number (but these appear to be of little interest and so have not all been noted below). For easy reference the album pages have been numbered by the archivist in pencil on the top right-hand corner.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted bedhead in IV.A.10., undated; cuid6409 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 1)
          Numbered 427. Also numbered 201. Initialled 'H'.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a piece of furniture in II.B.1., undated; cuid6410 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 2)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a porcelain jar in II.B.1., undated; cuid6411 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 3)
          Numbered 278. Initialled 'H'.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a piece of furniture in IV.A.10., undated; cuid6412 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 4)
          Numbered 366. Initialled 'I'
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of furniture in IV.A.10., undated; cuid6413 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 5)
          Numbered 368.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of furniture in II.B.1., undated; cuid6414 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 6)
          Numbered 367.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a frame in II.B.1., undated; cuid6415 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 7)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6416 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 8)
          Numbered 391.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6417 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 9)
          Numbered 390. Initialled 'L'.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6418 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 10)
          Numbered 392.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6419 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 11)
          Numbered 389.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6420 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 12)
          Numbered 388.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of an oval painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6421 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 13)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of an oval painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6422 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 14)
          Numbered 394.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6423 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 15)
          Numbered 385.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6424 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 16)
          Numbered 384.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6425 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 17)
          Numbered 379.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6426 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 18)
          Numbered 380.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6427 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 19)
          Numbered 370.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6428 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 20)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1., undated; cuid6429 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 21)
          Numbered 383.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1., undated; cuid6430 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 22)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with mythological scenes in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6431 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 23)
          Numbered 387.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1., undated; cuid6432 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 24)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1., undated; cuid6433 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 25)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1., undated; cuid6434 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 26)
          Numbered 460.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen (cupboard doors) in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6435 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 27)
          Numbered 399.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen (cupboard doors) in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6436 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 28)
          Numbered 400.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen (cupboard doors) in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6437 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 29)
          Numbered 401.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6438 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 30)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen in II.B.1., undated; cuid6439 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 31)
          Numbered 424.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen in II.B.1., undated; cuid6440 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 32)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6441 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 33)
          Numbered 417.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6442 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 34)
          Numbered 415.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6443 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 35)
          Numbered 416. The page is annotated "Bess Adams" (HMA's half sister).
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6444 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 36)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6445 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 37)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6446 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 38)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6447 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 39)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6448 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 40)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6449 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 41)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6450 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 42)
          Numbered 441.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.C.5. (Villa Sassetti), undated; cuid6451 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 43)
          Numbered 439.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1., undated; cuid6452 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 44)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.C.5. (Villa Sassetti), undated; cuid6453 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 45)
          Numbered 440.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6454 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 46)
          Numbered 374.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6455 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 47)
          Numbered 378.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6456 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 48)
          Numbered 377.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6457 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 49)
          Numbered 376.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in II.B.1.a., undated; cuid6458 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 50)
          Numbered 375.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in Chinese style in IV.A.2. [Villa Natalia], undated; cuid6459 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 51)
          Numbered 458.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel in Chinese style in IV.A.2, undated; cuid6460 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 52)
          Numbered 457.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of two painted panels with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6461 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 53)
          Numbered 456.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6462 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 54)
          Numbered 455.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6463 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 55)
          Numbered 454.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6464 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 56)
          Numbered 421.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds and 'Chinoiserie' in II.C.4. (now in Villa Colletta), undated; cuid6465 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 57)
          Numbered 420.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with 'Chinoiserie' in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6466 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 58)
          Numbered 422.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds and 'Chinoiserie' in II.C.4 (now in Villa Colletta), undated; cuid6467 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 59)
          Numbered 419.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6468 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 60)
          Numbered 418.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6469 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 61)
          Numbered 395.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6470 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 62)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with birds in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6471 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 63)
          Numbered 369.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen with birds in II.B.1., undated; cuid6472 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 64)
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen with birds in II.B.1., undated; cuid6473 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 65)
          Numbered 449.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted screen in IV.A.2., undated; cuid6474 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 66)
          Numbered 450.
        - Photo missing, undated; cuid6475 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 67)
          Numbered 470.
        - Photo missing, undated; cuid6476 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 68)
          Numbered 471.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with mythological scenes, undated; cuid6477 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 69)
          Numbered 398.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with mythological scenes, undated; cuid6478 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 70)
          Numbered 397.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with flowers in II.B.4., undated; cuid6479 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 71)
          Numbered 437.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with flowers in II.B.4., undated; cuid6480 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 72)
          Numbered 436.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with flowers in II.B.4., undated; cuid6481 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 73)
          Numbered 435.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a painted panel with flowers in II.B.4., undated; cuid6482 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 74)
          Numbered 434.
        - Photocopy made in 2004 of a work of art in Villa La Pietra (XXVIII. A.14.), undated; cuid6483 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 75)
        - Photos missing, un-numbered, undated; cuid6484 (Box 29, Photo-album IX., Page 76.-100.)
      - 1. Oversize green canvas album (unlabelled) containing photographs numbered 1-98
        This is a canvas bound album made by the Ditta Barbieri, Firenze with HA's ex libris. The photos are inserted into corner slips on the recto of each page (not pasted on to the page) and there are usually two photographs on each page. They are annotated by HA, and he has numbered them more or less consecutively on the page and almost always given the measurements of each work beneath the photograph. Above the photograph he has in some cases supplied the name of the artist or given an attribution, and has also occasionally noted 'stolen'. Some of the photographs are missing. The numbers listed below are those given by HA and correspond to the Reali negative numbers (for their glass negatives, see Series X.
        - Photo missing. Page annotated "Bernardo Daddi, 1.37 x 0.76, stolen", undated; cuid6485 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 1)
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.XXXII. D.2.-6.17.-75., undated; cuid6486 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 2)
          Annotated "Coppo di Marcovaldo, 73 x 1.03 -26.".
        - XXX. B.5., undated; cuid6487 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 3)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola con cornice lignea dorata e dipinta: Madonna col Bambino, i santi Pietro e Paolo e angeli. Nell'aureola della Madonna: "Ave Gratia Plena..." e nell'aureola del Bambino: "Ego Sum...". h. 125 l. 90 Siena, Sano di Pietro. Annotated "0.53 x 0,71 Stolen". See also II.B.1.XXX. B.5.-4.15.-33. A postcard has been kept here with the photograph of a similar painting by Sano di Pietro in the Martin A. Ryerson collection at The Art Institute of Chicago.
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.XXX. A.10.-8.15.-21., undated; cuid6488 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 4)
          Annotated "0,59 x 1,20 Bigallo Master".
        - XXXII. A.11., undated; cuid6489 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 5)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola in cornice lignea intagliata, dipinta e dorata con decorazioni a pastiglia: Incoronazione della Vergine. h. 147 l. 71 Mariotto di Nardo (?), fine del XIV secolo. Annotated "0,67 x 1,49".
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.XXXII. A.11.-2.17.-28., undated; cuid6490 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 6)
          Annotated "Mariotto di Nardo".
        - XXI. C.1., undated; cuid6491 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 7)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola centinata: Madonna col Bambino, Angeli e Dio Padre. h. 115,5 l. 74 Pseudo Pier Francesco Fiorentino. Annotated 0,49 x 0,91 [Photo Reali, Firenze] A postcard has been kept here with the photograph of a similar painting by Pier Francesco Fiorentino in the Musée Jacquemart-André. See also oversize, II.B.1.XXI.C.1. folder 176.
        - XXI. B.11., undated; cuid6492 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 8)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola: Madonna col Bambino e Cristo Benedicente con libro (Santo?) nella cuspide. h. 146 l. 70 Pietro di Giovanni Ambrosi, XV secolo. Annotated "0,56 x 0,83".
        - Duplicate of II.B.1.XXI. C.13.-1.14.-53., undated; cuid6493 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 9)
          Annotated "Dalmasio, 0,60 x 0,70".
        - Duplicate of II.B.1.XXI. A.4.-1.14.-12., undated; cuid6494 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 10)
          Annotated "Maestro di S. Martino, 0,60 x 1,05".
        - XXI. C.10., undated; cuid6495 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 11)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola cuspidata: S. Michele e S. Pietro nella cuspide. h. 126 l. 63 Luca di Tommè, XIV secolo. Annotated "Lucca di Tommé, 0,51 x 0,70" [Photo Reali, Firenze].
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.XXXII. A.18.-2.17.-36., undated; cuid6496 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 12)
          Annotated "1,30 x 0,715".
        - Duplicate of II.B.1.XXXII. A.19.-5.17.-41., undated; cuid6497 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 13)
          Annotated "S. Martino a Mensola 0,90 x 1,68".
        - XXI. B.7., undated; cuid6498 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 14)
          DIPINTO a olio su tavola con la Presa di Troia. h. 63 l. 181,5 Biagio d'Antonio, XVI secolo. Annotated "Biagio di Antonio?, 1,596 x 0,41" [Photo Reali, Firenze].
        - Photo missing, annotated "72 x 92 x 1,29", undated; cuid6499 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 15)
        - XXXII. B.1., undated; cuid6500 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 16)
          DIPINTO a olio su tela in cornice lignea dipinta e dorata: Ultima Cena. h. 137 l. 306 Scuola umbra degli inizi del XVI secolo. Annotated "1,06 x 2,74".
        - Photo missing, annotated "S. Francesco, 2,32 x 1,62", undated; cuid6501 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 17)
        - Duplicate of II.B.1.XXXII. D.4.-7.17.-86., undated; cuid6502 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 18)
          Annotated "Cristiani, 2,14 x 1,55 x 1,71".
        - Photo missing, undated; cuid6503 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 19)
          Page annotated "stolen, 0,43 x 0,59". A postcard has been kept here with the photograph presumably of a similar painting of the Madonna and Child with two saints and two angels by Sano di Pietro at the Ashmolean Museum, Oxford.
        - Near duplicate of II.B.1.XXX. A.4.-1.15.-9., undated; cuid6504 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 20)
          Annotated "0,81 x 0,55".
        - XXXI. D.1., undated; cuid6505 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 21)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola sagomata e parzialmente dorata: Crocifissione con S. Francesco ai piedi della croce e iscrizione in alto: "IHS Nazarenus Rex Iudeorum" e in basso: "S. Franciscus"(si tratta, della croce dipinta, proveniente da Londra, ricordata in un "Inventory" del maggio 1931, p. 10, ritrovato nella credenza della Camera Blu-LXV. h. 234 l. 161,5 Maestro di San Francesco, fine del XIII secolo. Annotated "0,43 x 0,58".
        - Photo missing, annotated "0,78 x 1,835", undated; cuid6506 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 23)
        - XXX. A.5., undated; cuid6507 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 22)
          DIPINTO a tempera su tavola: Il Beato Davino d'Armenia. Iscrizione: "Hic Iacet Corpus Sancti Davini De Arminea". Cornice sagomata e dorata. h. 73 l. 204 Maestro lucchese (?) del XV secolo. Annotated "1,89 x 0,57". See also oversize, II.B.1.XXX.A.5. folder 182.
        - XX. A.20., undated; cuid6508 (Box 30, Folder 1, Page 24)
          DIPINTO (scomparto di predella) a tempera su tavola con cornice lignea modanata dipinta e dorata: Morte di S. Rocco. h. 30 l. 50 Bartolomeo della Gatta (?) seconda metà del XV secolo. Annotated "0,41 x 0,20".